For a century, the wall stood
as a bastion of peace and security.
We no longer had to live in fear.
People grew accustomed
to living like cattle.
Then…
The Titans destroyed what we
had taken for granted.
The battle for humanity had begun.
Death reigned, claiming the lives
of soldiers and civilians alike.
The losses were staggering.
Even more shocking was the fact that
Titans were hiding among us.
Five years after the fall
of Wall Maria…
we managed to capture
one of those creatures alive.
A fellow soldier, Annie Leonhart.
And yet…
As the smoke from the battle cleared,
the next threat emerged.
What in…
- Guys, look.
What is that?
It's a Titan.
Inside the wall?
- Impossible.
Section Commander, your orders?
I don't know.
Is this just a coincidence?
Oh no, this doesn't mean…
Pastor Nick?
Listen to me.
Whatever you do, keep it out
of the sunlight.
THE BEAST TITAN
For now, we've covered the Titan
with sheets.
It seems to be sufficient.
We'll take extra measures tonight.
Understood.
Excuse me, but what are we
supposed to make of all this?
Never thought there'd be
Titans inside the wall.
Why would you? No one did.
A select few knew,
the rest were left in the dark.
Why aren't they saying anything?
This is a huge discovery.
What's the point of keeping it secret?
That's how it is.
The leaders keep everything secret.
All this chaos, and they couldn't
even come up with a good excuse.
Okay, what's going on?
Why a Titan?
Why is the Titan inside the wall?
And why would you keep it a secret?
I want answers, and I want them now.
There's no time for this,
I'm busy enough as it is.
My flock has been devastated.
I demand compensation.
Do you know who I am?
Let me down this instant.
If you insist…
Straight down alright?
Commander.
- Wait.
Let me ask you something.
Do you have any idea how many Scouts
have died because of these monsters?
More than you can count.
They died for your freedom.
I was with them.
I was prepared to give my life.
You're going to talk,
or you're going to fly.
I can always move on to the next
loudmouth who wants to challenge me.
They probably know a lot
more than you do anyway.
Let go of me.
That's what I was about to do.
- Then do it.
Don't test me.
- Don't.
You think I'm afraid to die
for my faith?
We do our duty,
no matter the cost.
I don't care,
the Lord is my shepherd.
Drop his humble servant.
Lord, deliver me.
Don't be so serious,
it was just a joke.
Come on, Pastor Nick,
tell us.
Are all the walls made of Titans?
At least tell me that.
Section Commander?
How long has it been since
I've felt this way?
Probably when I first went
outside the walls.
Talk about terrifying.
Quick, I have to tell
Commander Erwin.
The Titans have breached Wall Rose.
TWELVE HOURS EARLIER.
WALL ROSE - MINAWI DISTRICT
You know, my village is just
a little south of where we are now.
Oh, my village is pretty close too.
Why can't I go see my family?
Maybe I'll sneak away once it's dark.
I wasn't allowed to go home until
I was back to normal, so…
My parents always used to say
I was too small to be a soldier.
I was smart enough, though.
Top of my class, almost.
Someone's gonna eat their words.
If you want, I can help you.
Oh yeah? Why would you?
Doesn't this feel strange?
We're on standby in our
regular clothes.
We can't wear our uniforms,
we can't even train.
The crazy thing is, our superiors
are armed to the teeth.
We're inside the walls,
not on the front lines.
Who are we even fighting?
No idea, maybe they're just
scared of bears.
Yeah right, bears.
- You can fight bears with guns.
I think I hear footsteps.
What?
- Shut it, Sasha.
Are you trying to say that
Titans are coming?
That's only possible if
Wall Rose has been breached.
What's wrong, Miche?
Tomas, you need to get out of here.
Take three messengers with you.
Warn the others.
The chance of Titans hiding among
the 104th Cadet Corps is slim.
Multiple Titans are approaching
from the south.
Wall Rose has been breached.
I'm not kidding, I hear something.
Is everyone here?
- What is it, Nanaba?
We've got company.
About 500 meters south.
Titans are approaching.
There's no time to put on
your equipment.
I want everyone on horseback.
Evacuate everyone in the vicinity.
Get to it!
- The south?
But that's…
Are we certain the wall
has been breached?
I'm sorry, but lunch is
going to have to wait.
Miche.
Nine, in that group over there.
They must have come
through Wall Rose.
Damn it, we didn't even get
the chance to find out what those things are.
Now it's too late.
Humanity has lost, this is the end.
Not if I have anything to say
about it. We're not done yet.
Not yet. We only lose if we give up.
Remember that.
As long as we can still fight,
we haven't lost yet.
Once the Titans reach the forest,
we split up.
I want four separate teams.
With both recruits and soldiers.
On my signal, we scatter.
Alert the citizens, do not
engage in combat.
Which of you knows this
area well?
I do. My village is to the north.
I know this area like the
back of my hand.
Conny too, tell him.
What's wrong?
- My village…
My village is to the south,
that's where the Titans are coming from.
I can help, but after that…
Let me go home.
Alright, guide the southern team
and then go to your village.
Yes, sir.
- I'm coming with you.
Are you crazy? They'll be everywhere.
You think I care?
I'd do the same for you, right?
How about you? You coming too?
Of course, wouldn't miss it
for the world.
As you can see, this day marks
a low point in human history.
Pay attention. This is the moment
to give it your all.
Don't lose heart.
They're through the forest.
The enemy's right behind us.
Scatter, now!
Ride as fast as you can.
No, they've started running.
Gelgar, take command
of the southern team.
Sir?
Understood.
Is he using himself as bait?
I'm going after him, I can help.
Stay here, we can't afford
to lose anyone else.
Have some faith.
That man's almost as good
as Captain Levi.
He'll be fine, count on it.
Another fight?
It wasn't my fault,
they were making fun of me.
Of course, Mikasa came to
your rescue again?
Thanks, Mikasa.
We don't hit everyone
who's mean to us.
As an adult, you have to
choose your battles.
Being strong means knowing
when to hold back sometimes.
Protect Mikasa once in a while.
It fell, here.
Get some sleep, you must be tired.
No, I'm okay.
That thing has seen better days.
I'll get you a new one if
I can find one.
Eren, Mikasa.
The Titans have breached Wall Rose.
They're coming.
Why can't they just
leave us in peace?
Can you go?
As if I have a choice.
If I may, it was a wise
decision to entrust Miche
with leading the 104th.
If anyone can handle it, it's him.
Yes…
Let's hope so.
Only four left.
No, don't risk it.
I've bought us enough time.
Still, I can't help but worry
about that Abnormal.
Look at it, easily over 17
meters tall.
Gigantic.
I've never seen one
with fur before either.
It's just wandering around,
why isn't it attacking me?
Definitely an Abnormal, but…
There you are.
Seems I don't need to wait
until sundown after all.
It went for the horse?
Come on.
Hold on.
You must not have heard me.
I said hold on.
May I ask what that weapon is?
That thing around your waist,
the one that lets you fly.
I believe we speak
the same language.
Perhaps you're just too
afraid to answer?
I see you use swords as well.
Fascinating. That means you know
about our weak spot.
Oh well, I'll just take this.
Not yet, we only lose
if we give up.
As long as we can still fight…
we haven't lost yet.
Oh, you're free to move again.
Stop, please.
Oh, so you can talk.
What an incredibly clever idea.
Translation and resync:
OhItsStefan
Out of nowhere, Titans have
appeared within Wall Rose.
The recruits of the 104th Cadet
Corps scramble to warn everyone.
Meanwhile, Eren and the others
rush to save them.
After returning to her
hometown…
Sasha is forced to confront
her past.
$RG
Next episode:
"I'm Home"